Alexander Yap

2/15 Stradbroke Road Boronia, Victoria 3155 Mobile: 03 9028 5308

Email: alexyap1205@gmail.com

Professional Profile

Senior Software Engineer with more than 10 years of work experience in Research and Development, Systems Analysis and Design, Application Development, Systems Implementation and Project Leadership.

Core Skills and Abilities

Experience implementing and maintaining large scale software programs

14 years' experience designing, implementing and providing support for new software solutions, and development and assessment of existing infrastructure.

Extensive experience in developing real time processing applications

Successfully developed and maintained multi-threaded applications requiring performance intensive response.

Demonstrated experience in leadership

Extensive experience in technical leadership for various sized projects in the past 10 years. Have lead small teams to large teams providing software solutions.

Excellent troubleshooting and communication skills

Successfully provide timely support to customers, with the ability to negotiate effectively with both internal and external stakeholders.

Employment History

June 2006 – May 2016 Senior Software Engineer, Yokogawa Engineering International Singapore

Responsibilities:

- Propose specification for new software solutions.
- Liaise with stakeholders to obtain approval for specification.
- Software design using UML, prototyping and investigation.
- Provide direction to solution architecture.
- Conduct Design Reviews.
- Software coding using C#, WPF/WCF, ADO.NET, Multi-threading, SQL and unit testing.
- Conduct code reviews.
- System Integration and testing.
- Software documentation
- Troubleshooting software issues
- Participate in continuous improvement activities
- Coordinate with other overseas software teams.
- Provide support to testing teams.

November 2003 – May 2006 Software Engineer, Misys International Banking Systems Manila, Philippines

Responsibilities:

- Provide functional specification to internal stakeholder.
- Software design using UML, prototyping and investigation.
- Software coding using C++, Visual Basic, COM, ADO, Multi-threading, SQL and unit testing.
- Conduct code reviews.
- System Integration and testing.
- Software documentation
- Provide customer support
- Manage software releases using agile methodologies.

November 2001 – October 2003 Software Engineer, Fujitsu Ten Software Philippines

Manila, Philippines

Responsibilities:

- Software coding using C, Win32 programming, Visual Basic, SQL, Multi-threading and unit testing.
- System Integration and testing.
- Software documentation

Education

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Civil)

Manila, Philippines University of Santo Tomas

Graduated: 2000

Skills

Programming Languages:	Databases:
C# (.NET 3.0/3.5, WPF, Multi-threading, WCF,	SQLite
ADO.NET)	SQL Server 2000
Visual Basic	MongoDB
SQL	
C/C++	Others:
Francouselle	Danier Battanna
Framework:	Design Patterns
	Multi-threading
.NET 3.5, 4.5	UML
Prism	Scrum
WPF	RUP
WCF	
Tools	
Visual Studio 2008 / 2010 / 2012 / 2015	
TFS Client	
Enterprise Architect	

-	

Certifications

– Certified Scrum Master (Scrum Alliance Member: 000203307)

– Brainbench Certification in C# (Transcript ID: 5884523)

– Java Programming